<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Markus Bloom</title>
    <link>https://markusbloom.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Markus Bloom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markusbloom.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dreaming big or achievable</title>
      <link>https://markusbloom.com/posts/dreaming-big-or-achievable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markusbloom.com/posts/dreaming-big-or-achievable/</guid>
      <description>Dreaming big or achievable # From: 🌊 Project Oyster
My friend says big goals kill his productivity because reaching them is too unrealistic, though I find them motivating. An insane plan (like crossing the Atlantic Ocean on my yacht) gives purpose to my efforts, and I like imagining the day I reach it. In the end, it&amp;rsquo;s a personal preference that varies from person to person.
That&amp;rsquo;s what I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dreams vs goals</title>
      <link>https://markusbloom.com/posts/dreams-vs-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markusbloom.com/posts/dreams-vs-goals/</guid>
      <description>Dreams vs goals # From: 🌊 Project Oyster
When I moved to the USA, I decided to make my dreams become a reality, but I have failed to take any significant steps so far. This problem has haunted me for years: I have ideas, but they never become more than a dream.
I analysed why this is the case, and while doing so, I remembered a simple phrase: is it a dream or a goal?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus</title>
      <link>https://markusbloom.com/posts/focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markusbloom.com/posts/focus/</guid>
      <description>Focus # The art of not pursuing projects - how doing less results in more.
My goals are far away, and I worry whether I&amp;rsquo;ll ever reach them. This blog should document the path towards my dreams, yet I fail to take any steps. I have ideas, start projects, and then they all fade into nothing.
The reason: my lack of focus.
My biggest weakness is getting excited about new ideas before giving the ones I started the chance to grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I write too many words</title>
      <link>https://markusbloom.com/posts/too-many-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markusbloom.com/posts/too-many-words/</guid>
      <description>I write too many words # In school, I learned that writing is about the number of pages. In university, I got introduced to the word count; my papers had to be between 3,000 and 3,500 words, my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s dissertation at least 9,000 words, and to finish my Master&amp;rsquo;s degree, I had to write 20,000 words. In Ulysses, the text editor I use today, the word count is just one click away, and I can set daily goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, world!</title>
      <link>https://markusbloom.com/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markusbloom.com/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description> Hello, world! # A Blog in two categories:
Journal: Things that happened Meditations: Thoughts </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
